Based on the true story of the team that inspired a nation.
12 Mighty Orphans is a history, drama, action film directed by Ty Roberts.
Haunted by his mysterious past, a devoted high school football coach leads a scrawny team of orphans to the
state championship during the Great Depression and inspires a broken nation along the way.
Rusty Russell, played by Luke Wilson.
Juanita Russell, played by Vinessa Shaw.
Frank Wynn, played by Wayne Knight.
Doc Hall, played by Martin Sheen.
Hardy Brown, played by Jake Austin Walker.
Rodney Kidd, played by Scott Haze.
12 Mighty Orphans is a 2021 American sports film which was directed by Ty
Roberts from a screenplay by Roberts, Lane Garrison and Kevin Meyer.
It is based upon the non-fiction book Twelve Mighty Orphans: The Inspiring True
Story of the Mighty Mites Who Ruled Texas Football by Jim Dent.
The book is based on the Masonic School for Orphans in Fort Worth, Texas.
The film stars Luke Wilson, Vinessa Shaw, Wayne Knight, Jake Austin Walker,
Jacob Lofland, Levi Dylan, Robert Duvall and Martin Sheen.
The film was released in the United States on June
11, 2021 by Sony Pictures Classics.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of underdog, based on novel or
book, sports, war veteran, american football.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.